Mohammad Alzu'bi

Amman, Jordan +962796226992 mohammad.z@outlook.com

Experienced ASP.Net MVC Developer / Business Analyst committed to maintaining cutting edge technical skills and up-to-date industry knowledge. One of my strength is my ability to walk into a new environment and be functional immediately.

Skills

- C#, ASP.NET, .NET Framework, .NET Core, MVC, ASP.NET Web API, Entity Framework, Identity Framework, SQL Server, BI, HTML, CSS, jQuery, JSON, Razor
- Agile, Scrum, RUP SDLC
- Business Requirement Analysis
- Database Modelling

- Writing SRS, Proposals and User Manuals
- User Experience
- Usability Testing
- Use Cases, Test Cases
- Business Process Modelling
- Unified Modelling Language

Experience

JUNE 2014 - PRESENT

ASP.NET MVC Developer/ Princess Sumaya University for Technology, Amman

Responsible for analyzing and developing business web-based applications using ASP.NET & MVC approach. Developing *Online Dynamic Forms Builder* to eliminate paperwork. Participating in writing RFP documents for several bids. Providing technical consultations for the university departments to enhance and improve the IT infrastructure. `

SEPTEMBER 2013 - MARCH 2014

.NET Developer/ Grant Thornton Middle East, Amman

Responsible for developing and adding new functionalities to the organization auditing system. Maintaining and installing system applications. Defining IT objectives, business requirements for the organization. Making recommendations. Writing reports and documentation.

FEBRUARY 2012 - MARCH 2013

.NET Developer - System Analyst/ Microsoft Joint Venture (STS, NITC, Optimiza)

Responsible for analyzing and implementing medium scale ERP applications for government sector. Collecting the users' needs and analyzing the business requirements for a specific business domain. Performing Performance and Integration Test on the existing ERP Modules. Providing technical consultations and recommendations for several organizations in Jordan.

FEBRUARY 2009 - FEBRUARY 2012

.NET Developer/ TRiO Extensions, Amman

Responsible for developing and maintaining .NET Middleware and Backend SQL Server Databases for Content Management Solutions. Integrating new solutions into existing platform. Participating actively into planning the phasing out of legacy components.

Education

JANUARY 2009

Bachelor of Software Engineering / Al Balqa' Applied University, Salt-Jordan

GPA: 2.57 OUT OF 4.00

Certificates

NOVEMBER 2012

SQL Server 2008, Implementation and Maintenance / Microsoft, Jordan

EXAM NUMBER: 70-432 SCORE: 966 OUT OF 1000 TRANSCRIPT ID: 1020323 ACCESS CODE: D9E7C14B

TRANSCRIPT: https://mcp.microsoft.com/authenticate/validatemcp.aspx